technology greater noida
it's an immense pleasure uh to welcome
you all
to a wonderful leadership talk series
2020 which the institute has
initiated so we are joined
by a number of luminaries from the
industry from the academia
as well as future aspirants of the
industry along with my colleagues and
fraternity of vintec as well
dear attendees a good life is when
you assume nothing do more
need less smile often
dream big laugh a lot and realize
how blessed you are the curve balls in
our lives teach us more
you make a stronger and open doors to
unlimited possibilities
while we all strive to survive the
pandemic together
it has made us stronger and has also
brought us
closer few months back we would be
happily watching a tv series like
a day in the life of a ceo or following
business channels and magazines to know
about
business leaders little did we imagine
that we would one day be spending a
saturday evening
with one amazing leader and receive his
wisdom
on a critical topic like insurance
resilience in a rapidly changing karuna
virus
world our sincere gratitude
to the eminent guest of today mr parker
who is the managing director and ceo
at icici lombard he's a name to reckon
with
for his critical leadership positions in
diverse business areas
in the icici group and we are very
grateful
that he agreed to deliver this special
talk under the leadership
talks 2020 series on reimagining
insurance industry post covet 19.
i'm very happy to welcome some of the
friends
of our bibtex insurance fraternity
who have always supported us in our
mission um
i am very delighted to welcome mr bd
banerjee who's independent director
royal sundaram general insurance company
chennai
and he was formerly chairman managing
director the oriental insurance company
limited
as well as insurance ombudsman in mumbai
he's also joined by mr arun agarwal
who is currently on the board of kotak
mahindra general insurance
as an independent director and one of
his latest monograph
on insurance governance for world's
largest democracy
where bimtek was also a knowledge
partner
it lays down a complete insurance
governance
framework and it has been received very
well
by the insurance regulator as well as
the concerned ministries
in india he's been the ceo and md of
chula mandala
and he has had so many wonderful roles
in his corporate life we also have with
us mr kaushal k
mishra who's former ceo and managing
director
of tata aig general insurance company
limited
it's also an honor to have with us one
of our member of the board of governors
vimtek mr sabke ketan who leads the
kitaan legal associates and
he's developments of london business
school and also the member of bar
council of india
and we always are drawn by
his uh vision every now and then thank
you
at the outset i would like to invite
our director dr harvan's chat vedic
he has been leading the institute
in a very futuristic way and two decades
back when he decided that bimtech
should launch a pgtm program in
insurance
i'm sure that it was really good for our
institute and today we are being led by
so many ceos and leaders
of that industry our students gain
faculty gain
and on behalf of all the chairpersons
deans students and faculty members
i extend my warm welcome to all of you
and hand over
the session to our director for his
welcome address
thank you professor nisina
our esteem
chief guest who is going to address
our students faculty research scholars
uh mr bhargav gupta
our other guest mr vidi banerjee
mr arun agrawal
my colleagues from the insurance program
doctor abhijeet chatras professor marus
pandey
uh professor prateek predarsi professor
k krishnan
and also our young colleague
monica nippel so it's a great occasion
for us
to offer to our students
not only of insurance programs but from
other programs also
this leadership
talks series for the current year
already we could have another stalwart
from
the industry dr ajit ranade a few months
back
he is a group executive president and
chief economist
with aditya buddha group a renowned
economist of the country
so for the last couple of years we have
been invited inviting
senior leaders from the industry and
also from
the public life of the country
and the purpose is that students should
learn
not only from books or from classroom
interaction with their faculty they
should also
learn from the life lives and
achievements of
the corporate leaders social leaders
and we are thankful to mr bhargavdas
gupta for sparing time
today on this weekend
i have picked up some of the very
important learning for our students from
his profile
that he started his career with icici
group
in 1992 completed
more than 28 years
he is the ceo for icici lombard general
insurance company limited
for last one decade
he has been involved with various
businesses of icici
group but particularly i would like to
mention
the international banking group of icici
bank
he built its presence in 15 countries
within four years
and there is a case
on this big achievement at harvard
business school it is being taught
in various business schools of the world
so i think insurance industry
is very important for india
future destiny it is important
for the global economy particularly
after covert 19
a pandemic which has never
felt and seen for last hundred years
there is lot of talk about how to manage
future risk
coming arising out of disasters
pandemics
and also many other types of
risk associated with human lives
i would like to
just submit that in our vision
it has been mentioned that we are
developing ethical leaders
with entrepreneurial and global mindset
is striving for sustainability and
inclusive growth
so it is a vision we are trying to
practice in
our life and in our
practice we are preaching to our
students
that they should also try they should
also strive to become
ethical leaders with entrepreneurial and
global mindset
they should strive for sustainability
and inclusive growth in their future
life
it is true that in the very beginning
they will not get
leadership opportunities but definitely
some of them a few of them may like
become
leaders like mr bhargavdas gupta
and they will have to learn how
mr das gupta rose to this
high position while working tirelessly
following the vision of the company
where he has been working for last so
many years
so over to saloni and i
welcome our speaker for today mr
bhargavdasgupta
and i also welcome our other esteemed
guests whose names i have mentioned
this is a big occasion and definitely
it will be recorded in our
our newsletter as well as other
publications
thank you thank you so much sir and you
rightly said
in the vision we talk about developing
global
thought leaders and ethical leaders and
what a wonderful testimonial we have
today with us sir
when the course had started you must
have thought about nurturing such
leaders and you just mentioned that you
know one day we will soon have our own
ceos
at least you know we have these success
stories and one
such testimonial has joined us today i
feel very delighted and very proud to
welcome
vidisha and i'm calling her by her first
name because she
is a student of pgdm insurance
and from the 2010-12 batch she was a
gold medalist so that's a testimonial of
the kind of course we are running here
and that's the story walk the talk
today she's joined us because she
is going to tell us how she has gained
and how she has reached the position of
associate vice president and reinsurance
in icici lombard under the leadership of
mr parker so i thought that
the right opportunity for hidisha to
actually
introduce our eminent speaker of the day
in the leadership talk series 2020.
welcome vishan thank you so much for
joining
please let us know uh your journey with
mr das gupta and handing it over to you
welcome thank you thanks a lot miss
salone
good evening everyone good evening sir
indeed it is a great pleasure for me and
a big honor for me
to introduce my ceo mr bhargav dasgupta
at the institute where i have spent two
great years
bhargav holds pgdba from indian
institute of management bangalore
and a be mechanical degree from jadhav
university
bhargav is a courier icici man
haven't begun his stint at the earth
while icsa limited in 1992.
within the group he has held many
critical leadership positions
including project finance corporate
banking and treasury
e-commerce strategy international
banking and life insurance
he was ceo icsi economet limited
where he was responsible for private
equity investments
in the internet communication and
technology sectors
incubation of new internet related
business
and e-initiatives of various business
units of icici group
as also mentioned by chatham he
set up he has set up the international
banking group of icsa bank
and built its presence in 15 countries
within four
years which is a case study at harvard
business school
prior to his current role at icslm
at isis lombard he was the executive
director
of icc prudential life insurance
in 2009 bhargav joined icsa lombard as
mdn ceo
with him at the helm the company has
moved from strength to strength
and has consolidated its market share in
its preferred segment
and became the first non-life insurance
company to get listed on stock exchange
bhargava has also consistently pushed
for using technology
to provide innovative solutions which
has resulted in the company introducing
many firsts in the industry such as
virtual inspection and motor
bots which issue quotations for
corporate customers
and use of natural language processing
for to reduce health claim
approval time in past five years
that i have worked with the organization
i have
experienced first hand how these
solutions not only help solve customer
problems
but also make day-to-day lives easier
for us
as employees his another great
contribution
has been building a culture where
employees are empowered to take
decisions
it is a testament to his leadership that
when the covet 19 pandemic
hit the country and the economy earlier
this year
the company was not only able to move
seamlessly to
working from home but also able to come
up with new solutions for customers both
corporate and individuals
he is currently the chairman fiki's
insurance
insurance and pension committee and is a
director on board of bfsi sector skill
council of
india he is also a member of various
iidi
appointed committees like health
insurance forum
insurance advising committee etc
for a man who does so much he also
somehow manages the time to read
and keep himself updated on the
developments across the world
indeed his bookshelf which we can see on
many calls and even currently we can see
is an object of envy amongst many of us
he is also an avid runner having taken
part in many international marathons
i request mr bhagavddasgupta for his
insights
on reimagining insurance industry post
coverage 19.
thank you
thank you uh uh thank you bimtek thank
you
professor sinha and uh professor chatham
for giving me this opportunity
honestly it's a very very uh pleasant
surprise
to uh see that vidisha is also here
you know she's uh she's an outstanding
uh young leader
in the in the organization you know
we've worked reasonably closely because
she's in reinsurance
and you know given the criticality of
the function there is a lot of times
that we spend together
uh you know i can uh you know look at
her and see the quality of
students that you have in bimtech and i
didn't expect to see her here
so it's a it's a great uh pleasure to
see you uh
thank you sir thanks a lot indeed it's
just my pleasure
to be associated with the company and
the college and being able to
uh relate both of them thank you thank
you
so uh you know i won't you know waste
too much time
uh talking about uh you know anything
else but what i'll do is i'll
uh kind of give a overview of how we
think
uh things are going to shape up and you
know the whole idea was to give an
overview and then
probably have a more uh interactive
session
that's what i discussed with uh
professor
raj and i thought that would be more
helpful for all of you
and honestly speaking in this panel
today in this forum today we
have some uh you know leaders that i
have looked up to in the insurance
space some outstanding uh thought
leaders in the industry
and some people that i've worked closely
with so it will be
an absolute honor to share some of our
insights
i would love to others also join in if
they feel that they have
something to add to what i'm saying so
uh
let's just move to where what you want
to cover today uh the impact of covert
on insurance
you know covet has really affected all
of us um
you know you know who would have
imagined that we would be sitting uh
in our respective homes talking to each
other uh
on a platform that we had ever never
imagined uh
possible even three years back and it's
something that has become routine for us
uh but honestly this pandemic is first
and foremost a human tragedy
uh and it's something that has deeply
affected humanity
uh you know and the economy at large
and the stakes for individuals
businesses workers the economy overall
is really really extreme
where will this head i mean honestly
speaking no one knows
how this the course of this pandemic
will uh you know run through over the
next you know six months over 18 months
will
depend greatly on the vaccine that all
of us are eagerly
awaiting uh the arrival of but let's be
real even if we get a vaccine um
we will have take a lot of time to uh
actually you know administer it to to
all the
uh you know a countrymen across the
across the country that itself will take
you know months if not years
so in effect we have to mentally be
prepared to live with this
pandemic for at least a foreseeable
future
the impact as i said on this of this
pandemic is not just on
uh on health and all of our lives
i think the biggest impact has been also
in the economy
and uh one of the things that we debated
a lot
in the beginning of this pandemic when
everything got shut down
uh is would this recovery whenever
things recover
would it be v-shaped or which means a
sharp recovery
will it be a u-shaped recovery with a
little bit of time and then it'll pick
up
or will it be an l-shaped recovery you
know it will be flat for a long time and
then we'll pick up
i think increasingly what most people
are beginning to realize
is that it looks like a k-shape recovery
what i mean by a k-shaped recovery is
that there are some parts of the economy
which is
recovering faster maybe the organized
sector
of the economy maybe some of the better
well-managed companies are
gaining market share at this point in
time but unfortunately
there are a lot of people who are who
probably suffering a lot and certain
sectors of the economy of course
certain services sectors uh travel
tourism to give an example
but also a certain uh part of our
countrymen i mean
the particularly the urban poor so it's
a k-shaped recovery it's
recovering fast some part of it and some
part of it not
and we have to think about the impact of
this pandemic and the economic impact
uh in terms of how much this impact will
be over a period
to decide how much it will shape you
know where the industry is going to go
and one of the views that in the
beginning a lot of people uh had
uh was that it will be a temporary
impact i mean you know yes we will have
some
lockdown for some time uh you know
sometime later we'll
open up people will come back to work
and
the world will begin to look like it was
uh some time later
and the view was that typically you know
human beings kind of
get used to some of these changes and
move on in life so
the change will be temporary and in the
long term the change may not be very
very impactful
our belief right from beginning was that
it would not be so i think this is
a transformational event at a
civilizational level
uh what i mean by that is that if you
look at
some world events in the in the recent
past uh
let's say 911 something that affected
our industry a lot
had a huge impact on the travel industry
travel and tourism industry in terms of
the way
uh the industry was organized from a
safety perspective from terrorism
perspective
and it changed the way we you know took
flights and and we got used to it
but 9 11 was a sharp localized event at
a point in time
the current pandemic is something that
is uh impacting
many many more people over a long period
of time
and at a deeply personal level i think
across the world everyone has got impact
now you know all psychologists will tell
you that impacts of events of the
these nature leave a very very marked
impact on uh on human beings
and our belief is this will be one such
which means this will actually change
potentially geopolitics
it will potentially change the world
order it definitely will change
economics uh it will change the way we
conduct ourselves so there will be
societal change and there is clearly
going to be technology and
in that context we have to think about
what it
what it does to insurance now
uh in terms of uh looking at our
industry
our industry is clearly bank in the
center of this pandemic because we are a
risk industry
and when we think about how this is
going to change uh our lives
in the future first thing that we have
to think about is uh
how does it affect our consumers because
at the end of the day we are in
businesses of providing risk solutions
to our customers
and how they change because of this
event
will determine how we have to adapt as
an industry
and i think the first thing that comes
to my mind is that
this event will have a big impact
in terms of awareness and increased need
for personal insurance
you know this is not something that any
one of us wished on anyone else
but fact remains that because of this
event there is a greater awareness of
the need for protection particularly for
life insurance and health insurance
and there's been a lot of surveys done
by reinsurance companies you know
swissie has done something rj has done
something
across asia all research and all surveys
throughout the same uh
feedback that there is a lot of increase
in personal
uh insurance demand in in the minds of
consumers
so that's one change that we think will
happen the second change that we are
experiencing as we speak
is um uh changed expectation from
customers in how they consume services
clearly there are two types of customers
if i just keep it simple
one who are not as discovers and you
know who are willing to go out and
step out and go into crowded areas don't
worry about the risk
and there's a large part of customers
who are still worried about
you know contracting the disease and at
least that segment of customer is
expecting contactless service
when it comes to claims or policy
processing uh
across board most customers are
also expecting that you become you as an
insurance company
become a second source of trusted advice
uh it's not just it's not good enough to
solve for a claim when it happens
but advise me on my wellness or my
prevention
uh advise me on where i should go to
when it comes to taking a treatment
and you know be a more of a trusted
partner beyond just paying claims
so that is to me two big changes that we
are seeing people are expecting
you know contactless digitized services
and people are looking forward to
someone
uh you know it could be insurance it
could be someone else to provide them
advice that they can trust when it comes
to healthcare and personal protection
uh and of course you know as an
organization as a insurance industry we
have to see how we can provide that
that support the third thing that we are
seeing coming from customers is
uh you know as the new risks are coming
through
uh there is clearly a demand for new
product constructs
i talked about health uh in terms of uh
in health specifically as an industry uh
we had traditionally been providing only
ipd solutions that is if you
you know go to a hospital stay there for
24 hours we pay for the claims
that's not what customers are only
concerned about when they come when they
have uh you know when they look at their
healthcare
what customers are looking at is can we
provide a comprehensive healthcare
solution
to their needs and can we also provide
them
solution which reduces the risk of
further infection when they go to a
hospital
so for example can we think of providing
outpatient cover
where you go to a you know doctor not in
a hospital but
you know your your family doctor uh get
treated for something that doesn't need
hospitalization
pay for the pharmacy bills pay for the
diagnostic uh you know the test labs
your labs it said lab tests etc and
potentially do that on a seamless
paperless cashless process so that it's
convenient for me
they're also saying that you know i
would love to take teleconsulting why do
i have to go to a
visitor hospital at this point in time
because i don't want to take risk of
going to a hospital
so can you provide me delhi consulting
can you provide home-based care
you know for small ailments small
diseases you don't really need to
go to a hospital and in fact if you
provide me care
in my home uh the the risk of contain
you know infection comes down
and i'm more at comfort it's
really this is you know based on one
research that we've done about 28
percent of
indian response respondents are asking
for some of these
incremental features to their uh to
their policy and
honestly again they're looking for more
digitized more personalized cover
based on uh you know specifically
customized solution
uh driven by wellness platforms that
they are willing to uh
you know kind of join in so one of the
things that we are seeing is people are
willing to share their personal data
with you
if you are able to provide you know use
the data to provide them better products
and
better services so when it comes to
customized health insurance
using the data that they're willing to
share when they're coming on your
platform
for wellness solutions if you can give
them some benefits
they're happy for uh you know for uh
you're happy to provide that data
so that's one transformation that is
possibly coming through in the health
insurance space similarly as more people
are working from home
the demand for cyber is increasing uh
you know
as organizations we could manage uh
perimeter security as we call it when
everyone comes into our network within
the organization
we create firewalls and boundaries etc
and we manage it now as everyone goes to
their
homes and works from their homes you
have to think about how do you manage
the cyber risk and and this is something
that is clearly
uh you know increasing day on day and we
have to provide solutions to protect
uh you know corporates and retail
employees from cyber risk and that's
something that
you know is emerging as a bigger
opportunity
similarly for home india unfortunately
the home insurance penetration is very
low
but as you're working from home with
assets of the corporate
uh you know be a laptop or meet some
other you know devices that you have
which are corporate property and you're
working from home uh
again the demand for home insurance is
broadening beyond what traditionally was
home insurance
now there are possibilities of provide
cover providing covers which
take care of your personal assets as
also corporate assets that's
in another opportunity level at a
corporate level
uh i think you know all of you who
students of insurance have seen
the kind of debate that has uh developed
in the west
in terms of business interruption covers
uh
in india that debate never happened
because we never had any non-damage bi
covers
prevalent in india that clearly is a
need of the hour now how we
price it how we underwrite the risk etc
is something that we have to solve for
but clearly there is a big opportunity
for non-damage bi risk particularly for
smes
in events like this and one thing that
is being talked about a lot
is uh solving for the pandemic problem
and the pandemic risk is a
challenging risk to solve for insurers
because the
the tail risk is very high so the
solution that
people are talking about is pandemic
pools which limit the talents for
commercial insurance with some kind of a
public you know private private solution
at least in the initial period till the
pool gets built up
and that will help uh you know create
more resilience
and certainty for businesses if you can
provide these solutions
so clearly there is a a a big change in
terms of
the customer demand on um
need service and demand on you know and
products that is coming through
and last trend that we are seeing is
there is a bit of a flight to safety
uh so one of the things that we think
will will happen is some of the
better and stronger companies will uh
you know benefit for some time uh in
terms of customer
reference shifting to some of these
companies that's a trend that we are
seeing
across industry so what is the
imperative for
insurers what do we need to do to
address this need of
of consumers and another thing that i
want to talk about when i'm talking
about corporates is that our
insurance companies is that this
pandemic has told us
or taught us that there are there is
another way of working
which could potentially be positive in
certain aspects
and necessary in another but it's an
opportunity to
look at for the future uh so one of the
things that is clearly very clear to all
of us
is that all organizations have to become
much more digitized connected and agile
i mean we have to
work together in a uh in a remote
uh you know a manner where people are
sitting sitting and working from homes
but become but remain as
collaborative as connected uh as fast
in terms of uh finding solutions to uh
to customer needs
and as as effective as if we were
sitting together that means there's a
lot of transformation that organizations
have had to go through
both in terms of internal processes the
technology that we
put in but also the way we work and this
is probably a
change that is here for the long term
this is not just a temporary change in
lockdown period
you've probably read and seen that
globally a lot of technical technology
companies are saying this is the way we
will continue to work
our view is that this is actually an
opportunity to do many things
when you think about your employee based
you can give a more flexible way of
working you know someone could decide to
work two days at home and three days in
in office
when things become normal someone could
decide that i want to work from my
hometown
in you know let's say indoor though my
you know base offices
is in mumbai and if the organization
allows me to do that
i would be happy so there are these
opportunities that are
opening up for which organizations need
to
reorient the way they uh you know they
go about doing their day-to-day
operations so that's one thing
in terms of staying more connected uh
allowing more remote working and
yet becoming more agile to solve uh
customer needs that are changing very
very rapidly
the second uh you know imperative for
insurance organizations and in fact any
service organization is
to implement digital at scale i mean
there are enough whatsapp jokes that
have been going around saying that who
drove your technology your digital
transformation whether the cto or the
ceo
or covet and honestly the answer is
probably all three for most uh
most companies what govit has done is uh
uh scale this or or you know
you know make this change come through
much faster than what it would have
otherwise
all organizations have realized that we
need to become
much more automated and digitized to be
able to compete
now when you talk about digitization it
is not just about selling policies
it is also about how we how we as an
organization do everything that we do
as an organization be it for policy
sourcing be it for
normal policy servicing it for claim
servicing be it the way we operate
as an entity within ourselves across
with our agents and our
employees all of that needs to be
digitized in some way or form
and this honestly is
you know not only an imperative for
growth it's possibly an imperative for
survival if you don't do this
as an organization you may not remain uh
viable in the long term so this is the
second imperative for insurance
companies as
an as i said for any company third is
for our industry there is an opportunity
to modernize our
distribution channels what i mean by
that is that
there is a lot of debate that most
policy sourcing will shift to online
channels we don't believe
that some of some customers will you
know will definitely shift to digital
channels
and as a percentage digital channel
sourcing may increase and would increase
but india is a country where we don't
believe
all the customer base will shift to
digital channels we believe that
customers would still want to have
interaction with
their trusted agent we'll need some
broker to give them advice
we'll need to go to uh you know maybe a
dealer to buy an insurance policy
will go to a bank to buy a policy so you
have to
think of being a company which provides
all means of accessing your your
products and services
across various distribution channels
however the distribution channel can
be made much more digitized and become a
more of a hybrid
channel where there is a lot of physical
touch but equally there is a lot of
technology making the process very
convenient smooth and low cost
uh you know for for you so this would
mean uh completely
for example from agency side you could
mean completely online recruitment
management
uh training you know using uh using
videos which we've been doing in
these times but this could be the way
for the future uh similarly using uh
you know rpa tools the robotic process
automation tools uh
uh advanced analytics to you know help
them you know sell more policies
uh you know completely digital app-based
solution platform accelerating platforms
so these are things that
that will become absolutely essential uh
for companies uh
you know in the in the short term forget
you know medium and
long term fourth thing that we are
seeing
is becoming even more possible is the
point that i made that lot of
customers are expecting insurance
companies to become their trusted
risk management partners it's not just
good enough to pay claims
but can you help me with my risk so when
it comes to
individual customers can you help me
with wellness and other solutions so
that i don't fall sick
similarly for corporates can you analyze
my claims data and tell me how i prevent
a claim from happening
uh can you look at my marine transit uh
you know losses and tell me how i
prevent a loss
going in and today there are a lot of
technologies this is not just to do with
covid
as a company we've been doing this for
almost six seven years now
but i think covet will accelerate this
uh this change
and with these technologies like iot
telematics or using drones
you can actually uh you know solve for
this risk management solution
for corporates much better than what you
could have in the past
and last point that i'll make for
corporates is our insurance companies is
that
i think this is a time which where you
have to become very very cautious and
careful
because of the uncertainty in the market
and you have to be
very sensitive sensible about how you
manage your business and one of the
things that you have to do is
really optimize your cost again you're
bringing more efficiency in operations
while you invest in training people you
know you're building up your
employee base and making them more
competent and building distribution but
all the unnecessary uh you know flab in
the system has to be tightly controlled
because these are difficult times so
these five would be in my mind
uh the imperatives for insurance company
if they want to sustain and
and do well uh in the long term but i'll
end with
one point that uh you know personally
has been very you know
close to my heart and i think this has
been a wake-up call this event has been
a wake-up call for
uh corporate sector in general not just
insurance
i talked about the fact that we've had a
k-shaped recovery
and i wanted to talk about that because
i wanted to highlight the point that
you know in this crisis uh there is
still a large
population of people who are still
suffering and i think one of the things
that
uh corporates across the world are
beginning to realize
is that for 50 years we've probably
changed you know
you if she you know we've gone after and
chased the false
god the view was that the only role and
responsible the corporates had was
shareholder capitalism your only
responsibility was to
ensure that your shareholder made money
that's an important objective
but that's not the only objective i
think increasingly
uh corporates and at least the good
corporates are beginning to understand
that you need to think about all
possible stakeholders meet your
employees
meet your customers be your distributors
be society in enlarge what are you doing
as an organization
which is helping society in a positive
manner
rather than just uh you know focus on
making money for your shareholders as i
said making money for your shareholder
is absolutely vital because if you don't
do that you don't exist
but you have to do it in a manner that
is positive for society in
in its entirety and that's something
that uh
uh i think the events that has happened
in the in the last
you know few months uh particularly
let's say what happened in the migrant
crisis
i think that uh realization has probably
got
uh further enhanced at this period i
hope that we as
you know corporates don't forget this
moment and remain true to
uh stakeholder capitalism rather than
shareholder capitalism i personally am a
big believer in capitalism rather than
socialism
so i don't want to message something
which means that we are talking about
something else
but the way we organize ourselves uh has
to keep in mind has to be in a manner
that keeps in mind
society at large and as an insurance
company we have a big role to play in
that
in that sense where as i said we can do
a lot more
in terms of helping our customers in a
meaningfully positive way
again using some of the technology uh
tools that are coming uh you know
becoming available to do that well and
that's something that uh
at least nice is hello but we keep
trying to do
so that's what i want to cover and uh
you know
as an overview and then take questions
from
uh any of you thank you
thank you so much sir that was very
enriching and i'm sure
uh everyone has a lot to take
from your session today uh at this point
of time
i hand over the session to the
chairperson of insurance program dr
abhijit chaturaj who is himself for
chartered insurer as well as he is well
known
in the field of research and training
and consultancies in this
industry and academia so uh welcome
abigail
sir i hand over this session to the qa
and um
let's let's invite and uh many many of
these comments are already here
uh thank you so much professor salani
and welcome back sir
uh i start with a lighter win in the
sense that
sir you spend quality time in banking
then life insurance and for the from
in general insurance as the captain of
the industry
which role did you like the most the one
in bank or one in life insurance or in
general insurance you know when i
when i was moved when i moved from the
bank
uh initially i thought my first love
will always remain banking
um having you know started my career in
banking and uh
it's it's natural right your first job
is something that you uh hold very close
to your heart
and honestly there's a lot that i got
from banking and i
found it very exciting particularly my
last in terms of setting up the
international banking
but but a few months into general
insurance particularly
i found this sector very very exciting
and the fact that i've
you know i've been happy to do this job
for 11 years is probably a testimony
um uh to that fact i think one thing and
i keep saying this and you know since
uh you have your students here
one of the things that i realized coming
in general insurance
and particularly as an engineer is that
this is a sector within financial
services
where you can really learn a lot and you
can
leverage your technology uh you know our
engineering skills to some extent
more than any other part of financial
services and i'll give a couple of
examples
um this is a this is a sector which is
really a
sector where you need to go deep into
the underlying uh
you know underlying drivers of an
industry so let me give you a couple of
examples so if you're looking at a
auto insurance you really need to
understand an automobile much better
than if you were doing
auto financing when you give a loan you
happen to understand the credit if you
do insurance
you have to understand the risk but also
understand when you are
handling claims uh a complete uh
perspective on the auto
including car part car parts and you
know how to repair them
at that level so if you are interested
in in knowledge at a second level this
industry is fascinating the other thing
is that
this industry can actually deploy
technology to do a lot of things which
is very very
interesting i talked about some of these
rpa tools or iot or telematics etc
that's very unique to gi so gi is an
exciting space i i just love this
industry
thank you so much what about the loss of
to the banking industry was
definitely again to of general insurance
industry
hope we will continue to lead the
industry in days to come
coming back to serious question now the
next
normal requires comprehensive and very
ambitious
response across five
areas one is how do you resolve to come
out from this crisis
the resilience everybody is talking
about
and then the most important
your talk was you revolved about
re-imagination
and reform one of the issues that you
also touched
during this discussion was mitigating
the risk for your employees that was the
big biggest challenge that you faced
and then you had to also ensure
operational
continuity how did you really you said
that's now that
one can work from indoor if he wants to
work from indoor
his headquarters maybe in mumbai or some
other places
so how did you look at it and how did
you come out of it
what was the result before you when the
kovid
before before or everybody in the
industry
yeah so i guess all of us you know kind
of where put
in the deeper end of the pool so we had
to learn to swim right
thankfully as a company we had been
investing in a lot of uh
you know digital tools we most of our a
lot of our internal
uh workflow systems are on the cloud we
had you know microsoft teams as a
company which were already using that in
certain parts of the organization were
using
so we had the tools but honestly
speaking all of us were not i mean
all our meetings were physical maybe
some video conferencing we never use
teams for our team meetings for example
we had to get used to at leadership
level all of us had to get used to that
but i think the first principle that we
said was that
employee safety is most primary at this
point in time
that was very that was very clear in her
mind and we kind of started
preparing for some kind of a bcp you
know business continuity planning
uh about two to three weeks before the
lockdown happened and that was
you know thankfully we kind of a bit
early in that we were beginning to see
what was happening in europe and we were
worrying about it so we started
preparing for it
so when we moved into london a lot of
things had already been
put in place uh but what we're now
seeing is that
uh when we are thinking about this way
of working going ahead
uh we see this as potentially you know
and positive opportunity in the sense
that we can give a choice to employ as i
said
uh we've done certain things and we will
continue to do some more things for our
employees so one of the things that we
did was uh
give data cards or broadband
connectivity to you know specific uh
people who didn't have some of those
things
um we giving you know let's say laptops
to everyone we give
headsets to people who need headsets we
are now
uh you know this quarter we will uh
start giving out
ergonomic chairs to employees uh desks
to employees who are once it for their
home
so basically giving them the basic tools
that
people would get to have at home and we
are
yet now not kind of at least in the
bigger cities we have
large offices where normally come we are
not asking people to come to office if
they're
you know productive from home they're
productive from home and i think what i
talked about in terms of uh
you know the opportunity these are
opportunities that we think will evolve
uh you know i think geography is history
uh people can sit in
uh as i said in indore and work for a
bombay based company and even a us-based
company
so that's something that we should take
advantage of as an
edge what kind of i.t
preparedness was for because the
critical services
were needed to be delivered through it
platform
uh or was the industrial ready for this
kind of i.t
preparedness or all of a sudden uh
everybody was found in a tz and never
knew how to come out of it
so again president i guess is different
across different companies so as you
know first april is a big month for
uh corporate business in india
absolutely uh and if you look at
smes smes are also uh you know in the
similar boat
so one of the things when we went into
lockdown in march we were worried about
uh
i mean a lot of people would worry about
it but uh what we had been doing
uh even before this is uh preparing the
organization for a digital
approach in any case it was not
something that we got it got triggered
because of this
so we had for example um digital
platforms through which you can source
policies
and you know even as i said before
corporate policies
we had digital processes so you can you
know even before this covered event
an agent in uh you know in in raipur
on saturday evening could decide to
issue a policy
where no human being would underwrite
the policy it was a
robotic process automation tool that we
had anyway built um
and using that tool for almost most of
our you know
products some products we couldn't but
most of our products was uh
so we could do that so in the month of
april for sme policies where it's not
uh retail simple standardized policies
each are customized
you know you know difficult uh you know
complicated
policies 90 of our policies were issued
digitally come to claim service we had
started a virtual inspection process
which is someone you you know customer
or a garage can
use their mobile phone and get a survey
done where our surveyor doesn't need to
travel to the
location they can do it from the comfort
of their office
now just move that office location to
their home location everything else
continues
so we had 100 of claims inspections in
the first month a month and a half
for auto and uh happening on the
instruct
app as we call it and similarly there
are uh you know other
things that so i think as an
organization if you kind of
believed in digitization you had to ramp
it up for anyone who hadn't it must have
been a big struggle
right so we needed one study and we
found that health has all of a sudden
become the new priority
for most of the it's going to come out
in a book that
bimtech will publish in a couple of
months time
now the greatest challenge that i or
anybody in the industry
foresee is that this this
renewed awareness how this
renewed awareness can be sustained in
days to come
it's a big opportunity area people are
looking at health insurance and other
form of insurance health insurance and
life insurance in particular
this is an opportunity area to build on
this opportunity how are you going to
sustain this
opportunity will it translate in more
penetrations
more take for insurance product in days
to come
uh again our view is the the answer is
yes
uh as i said event of this nature is not
something that people forget
uh in a short time uh people i think
that you know i was
talking to someone a friend of mine
whose parents stay in
a place in mp a small town in mp
in davas and he was talking about how
his local milk guy was
explaining to him the importance of
insurance and i the question that i
asked him is that
does that person think that insurance is
like an atm card you
you know pay a premium and you
definitely take the money out he said no
he understands the concept that
you don't get a claim every year if you
fall sick you get the claim
that's music to our ears right in
insurance so i think there is a
realization of importance of
insurance and i don't think it's going
to go away
what we have to do as an industry is to
really solve for
true needs of customers if you are if
your product is useful
people will buy it and when i say true
needs as i keep saying that insurance is
not just about
claim settlement it is also really
helping customers with their health
needs
which means the continuum of care which
means
wellness preventive advisory and all of
that and if you can do all of
you know that all of that and i'm sure
the health insurance industry will move
in that direction
uh my sense is that the demand will of
course this year has been a spike it may
not sustain at this level next year
but i think there's a step change in the
overall demand for health insurance
in the long term it's not a short term
and that reminds me of
what we normally customer engagement
and today people are talking in terms of
digital customer engagement
is that going to happen uh
according to you so let me give you an
example of from our
experience right from icc lombard so we
had launched
uh an app called i'll isis loma take
care i'll take care
so that is your kind of an acronym i'll
take care
um where we provided all of those so we
provided uh
an opt policy uh we did it for you know
b2b customers corporate customers
uh where you could uh do a telehealth
consulting service
you could after the telehealth
consulting the doctor would give you the
prescription the prescription we are
tied up with e pharmacies the
drugs would be delivered at home um
after that if you wanted to go to a
diagnostic center for tests that was
covered in the network
all of that completely paperless
digitized and we had
uh you know advisors for uh you know
you know you know basically expert
advice that was available
we had a kind of a concierge service if
you needed to go to a hospital we gave
you
choices and and some suggestions on what
is good what is bad
we had second opinion and all of these
pieces were there
uh what in this period when uh the the
in the last six months uh since we had
launched it last year the number of
downloads very small this uh six months
the downloads have grown
uh roughly about seven times in this
period the number of tele consultants
consultation that people are doing is
increasing month and month so
you know it's not as if what will happen
i think some of this is already
happening
uh may not be across the industry but uh
my sense is that companies that take the
lead in doing this more
will we believe benefit in the long term
one question coming from a student he
wants to understand
how can the insurance industry revamp
its operations by embracing
blockchain technology in claim
processing and reducing
over dependence on tpa
so as a company we don't we have our own
internal team we don't use a third party
administrator
but i think the question is a very very
good question it's not just from a tpa
perspective even for us
uh blockchain technology could help us
in terms of streamlining the process
with hospitals
and making it a better service
experience for customers i mean what
happens with customers today
when they the day they wait you know one
discharge
uh we get the bills from the hospital
maybe an hour before
uh you know the discharge time and we
process it and give it back
and then there's some two and four and
the customer is waiting and at times it
takes couple of hours for the customer
to get discharged
it's not a pleasant experience now if
you can actually use blockchain
uh you know as the customer is being
treated on a real-time basis some of
this information could flow to us
we could actually keep the files
processed and when the customer is
discharged it is a smooth process
without any
checking at that point in time so there
are a lot of possibilities that are
that are there but obviously it's a you
know you know you need
two hands to clap so as an industry and
the hospitals you have to come together
and do some of these things
to make it happen uh opportunity is
definitely there
a blockchain with the service provider
that's hospital is understandable
but what about the blockchain across all
the couriers all the insurance providers
fraud is one area which is adopting all
kind of business
so fraud elimination the blockchain has
a big role
in fraud elimination absolutely
absolutely in fact one of the things
that we've done uh
in with some of the insurers in bombay
at least because we were all
you know some of us in bombay kind of
managed to get it together
is on um on the motor side we are doing
exactly that
as a pilot uh we've experimented with
that and it actually works well
uh on prevention of fraud and prevention
of let's say
uh miss declaration on uh claims
experience in the past last year you
know
one of the things that we see is people
don't declare the previous year's claim
to get in you know
no claim bonus yes so those things can
be eliminated so those are things that
are
we've experimented it's not scaled up uh
obviously
we can do a lot better as an industry on
that another question that i'm getting
is
what are we are experiencing resurgent
of virus in us
and europe european countries what is
your outlook for the next six months
is it going to impact risk profile and
hence the risk management
of insurance industry you know any
expert who's predicted anything to
this virus has proved to be you know a
false expert right so i don't want to
say that i know what is going to happen
with this virus
i think what we've seen is in terms of
the claims data we've seen
we think the numbers seem to have peaked
in september and october seems to be
roughly kind of flat to slightly lower
but we also worry about a second spike
because of festive
season that we are going through at this
point in time uh we've seen what
happened in kerala the second spike
happened uh past
post onam so that remains a risk for us
um the only uh you know argument that
some experts are given i mean i'm not a
doctor or epidemiologist so i can't
comment on this but what
some of the doctors are saying is that i
think the percentage of people who've
already
uh you know got in you know build
immunity
antibodies is much higher in india so
the risk is relatively low but i don't
think that's a
safe bet to have i think the risk of
some amount of spike is there in may be
around december
one question i'm getting from bangladesh
and the
gentleman asks uh what would be the
strategy for an
insurance company to make the demand of
health insurance coverage for
pandemic uh like kobe 19. we had
initially an apprehension that the
kovid is not covered pandemic is not
covered
uh the regulator and the insurance
industry came together to dispel that
doubt
maybe in bangladesh where you do not
have the
independent indemnity-based health
insurance policy
they have all benefit-based health
maybe this reservation or doubt comes
from that
will do you see that health insurance
this is the right time health insurance
business to take off
in a big way absolutely and it is taking
off so
you know like just to comment on the
gentleman's question
you know when the covent event happened
none of us had
knew about it none of us had dissipated
this right uh so we didn't price for
this
but i think as an industry i am happy
that we took a very responsible stance
that we will pay for those games because
if you get hospitalized for any reason
on an individual policy we should pay
for it and uh
you know initially some there was some
doubt because i think one or two
companies had
raised some doubts about it uh we had
clarified as i said
right in the beginning that we would pay
for those claims and the regulator also
said the same thing so that was good
uh because we've seen this in certain
countries because people have said
pandemic is not covered
so we will not pay for code of covert
claims uh we believe that is not correct
uh it's come at a big cost for us as an
industry but uh so be it and that's why
we are here
so i think i don't know if in bangladesh
you have the same approach i have not
studied it
but if you've you know looked at the
indian indian industry our
popular product which is as professor is
talking about the indemnity product
which pays for which really indemnifies
the cost of
hospitalization those policies are
paying for uh corporate benefit policies
are fixed benefit they basically spell
out
the diseases for which there will be a
payment so those policies don't cover
covert so they will not pay
but indemnity policies here in india are
paying for covert claims
uh professor you are you got i think you
got muted
sorry sir this is a question coming from
mr saket ketan and
he's asked this question data is the new
fuel
what preparedness is lombard adopting
for the imminent
passing of data protection act being a
lawyer this is the question
coming today to answer tough questions
right
yeah so uh you know obviously this is
something that we have to gear up for
um we've studied the data protection act
and
we obviously have to ensure that we are
very transparent with our customers
in terms of how we what data we take how
we store it and how we use it
uh our view is that you know it's it's a
very it's a very
uh kind of dichotomous world right at
one level people are very worried about
uh you know data you know personal uh
data
uh concerns um and equally they're very
open to shared data i mean you're seeing
what happens in
any social media today so our take is
our you know talking to customers is
if we are able to give back something
meaningful
something valuable using the data that
the customers you know shares with us
i don't think and we don't misuse that
that data i think we are fine
you know and customers are quite happy
to work with companies there and that's
something that we have to
get used to so we have to think uh
creatively about
how do we use data in a meaningful
manner for customers
that's what we have to gear up for
another question coming from mr niles
satay as you all know mr satya was
member life insurance
he puts this question has there been
quantum
jump in cyber insurance post pandemic
everybody is asking that question hello
sir good to
uh you know chat with you even on this
platform uh
you know satay is a man that i think in
industry we have a lot of respect for
um so so honestly um we've seen some
growth
a couple of companies a few companies
have launched retail cyber policies
that's picking up in terms of uh you
know internal numbers
but as you know the base is very very
small and this is
even these increased growth numbers are
not going to move the overall industry
you know gwp much but increasingly and
there's a lot of
effort that at least some of us are
taking in terms of education on cyber
side
there is clearly you know even even when
we are talking about smes we are seeing
some interest coming through in terms of
cyber and crime policies
uh corporates of course are much more
aware and increasingly we are seeing
some
interest in the retail segment as we are
launching retail products so it's just a
small segment
it's growing but it's uh our sense is
that it's it's
not yet reached a meaningful proposal
proportion
but the opportunity is large uh may i
also
convey my sincere gratitude to mr niles
satay
he has been always very very supportive
to bimtech and
academics uh may i ask mr saket
if he wants to add something on data
protections
mr uh gupta in the beginning said if
any of this eminent panelists want to
add anything
uh mr ketan if you want to add something
on that
thanks dr chattaraja barbara sorry to
put you on a
spot on that absolutely not apologies
uh well uh i think you know there is the
eminent passing of
uh the data protection act in india uh
and it is
comparable and in some ways more
draconian than the gdpr
legislation we have in yours yeah to my
mind businesses in india would need to
prepare
very carefully to the manner in which
data is managed
in particular because the act actually
makes a senior
senior leadership team accountable by
making it a criminal offense for breach
yes both from an industry perspective
which means cyber
security response time as well as
in terms of protection all three needs
to be
ramped up so the way i look at it
is historically as you mentioned
parker indians don't consider to be
considered data to be private
and therefore there is a dichotomy in
the indian economy
where everything is available and you
have an act that is going to be passed
which is going to be making the
disclosure of data or the hacking of
data a criminal offense
so it's something that industry needs to
grapple with
and come to terms with and as you
mentioned as far as lombard is concerned
the protection of data and the real use
of data
becomes critical yes absolutely those
companies that
do that will actually um
you know uh distinguish themselves
uh from others and that's where success
will come yeah
you have to be responsible about it and
it's it's significantly more challenging
because of
the overall environment of cyber we all
we are
all obviously conscious of that but it
is
it is how you go about your intent
intentions is what will be important
absolutely thank you so much for joining
and
giving your uh valuable uh uh in
insight on that particular matter coming
back to question
uh mr das gupta uh one question is
coming from a veteran
from bangladesh mr qazi muhammad murtaza
himself was a very well known insurer
of at his time his question is very
simple when insurers are paying more
claims
and earning less premium how can they
invest for
advanced technology so the answer is
they can't
so that's why we keep saying uh and i'll
just give you an
indian statistic for the whole industry
for this
body so if you look at the indian
industry's profit after tax
from 2008 to 2020 right 12 years
you would expect i mean normally i'll
ask a question and ask for responses
which i can't hear i guess but
if you expect you would expect some
growth maybe you know five percent
compounded growth 10
compounded growth because of the time
that india's you know grown a lot
uh what you'll be surprised to hear is
that the industry is de-grown
by if i remember the number correctly
about 12 compounded as in
what we were earning as an industry in
was four or five times more than what in
fact today we are you know
as an industry we are kind of loss
making as an industry collective
so as an industry if you look at in the
year for 2020
the total profit after tax for the
industry was a minus 1400 crores
but if you look at four top four
companies in terms of profitability
uh the profits of the top four companies
is close to four thousand crores
right so that means that there are some
companies who are losing a lot of money
now those companies are not able to
invest in technology because you don't
you know that's the point that i made
that
you know if you think about running a
business you have to think of all
stakeholders
including the shareholder and you have
to make money because without that you
can't
invest and forget investment i think the
bigger damage that that this does
is that you become very irresponsible
about even claims
because you're struggling to pay claims
because your cash flows
are being challenged so making some
reasonable profit is absolutely
important for
investment in distribution and
technology in penetration one of the
reasons why i believe penetration hasn't
happened is because we've not invested
in
as a category as an insurance category
in terms of awareness creation in terms
of distribution into smaller towns
and that's largely because of very poor
underwriting that we've had as an
industry collective
some of us have not been we've been much
more cautious and quite a few companies
and i think those are companies which
are able to invest
so i took some questions from the uh
budding youngsters who are going to
become the leaders in days to come
so one of my students asked this
question how has the analytics
enable the leaders across the different
industries and geographies
to more effectively handle the
challenges present
presented by these unprecedented times
what role analytics is likely to play in
days to come
well it's absolutely vital i mean as i
keep saying that you know insurance is
probably the original data sciences
industry
right today everyone talks about data
and data science but insurance was
probably originally the first
industry which used mathematical models
and looks and looked at data
we've kind of you know kind of
lost a bit of uh you know our computer
advantage in that sense from those days
but
uh i think that's the way to think about
you know building your business
in future so if you think about what i
mean i'll just give you a couple of
examples so we talked about this
creating something meaningful for
customers using customer data
uh as an industry we've been very
transactional
at a product level today on a on a
digital platform maybe an app-based
platform where customers are willing to
uh you know give their health risk
assessment give their
you know step count give the you know
kind of uh
you know uh wellness platform that
they're operating on or the
or their the behavior that they have in
terms of
uh taking care of you know exercising
etc you can use some of those data to
uh potentially give them some certain
benefits be it in terms of extra covers
or
you know some freebies health here and
there etc and there are many companies
in
globally which have done that uh coming
to let's
say i talked about ai and ml uh today we
are able to do that i mean
as i said 60 of our health claims we
don't get a doctor to see the claim
it's done through a machine learning
engine that we build about a couple of
years back
that's because of data of the past we've
used the data to train the engine and
that's how the
engine operate today on a on a mobile
phone uh say there is a
you know breaking in your auto insurance
and normally we will
send a survey to check for damage
today we have a solution we just point
your app at the damage you take a few
pictures
and the app you know using ai figures
out whether it's a damage or not and
it tells you and passes of the insurance
policy so those are
abilities that we've been able to build
because of data uh you know fraud i mean
we've
used our analytics engine analytics team
to build a ml based fraud engine which
improved our previous you know solution
that we had
by almost 10 points so every part of our
business
data is vital for uh for you know
creating the difference between you and
the next guy who doesn't use data
and that's how you will in a very highly
competitive industry that's how you'll
stay ahead of the curve my next question
is
is virtual health likely to be the next
reality next frontier
we you know we can't call ourselves
health experts but
if you study uh the sector from uh
from a distance with a certain
perspective uh
you would argue yes if you see some of
the work that is happening
in digital health in in
particular in silicon valley i think it
will completely transform health care
our view is that in fact
if you see some of them talk to some of
the experts there the view is that
10 15 years from now health will be
completely personalized
it will not be you know a standard
process
and the demand for hospitalization will
come down and it will be completely as i
said digitized and personalized and
customized health
based on your maybe your genetics or
your
activities uh or your you know the the
the small
you know what will monitor whichever way
you want to call it
uh so our view is that it will be a
digitized health
model in the next 10 15 years whether it
will happen in that time i don't know
but
it will definitely happen in the near in
the future
my reason is that country like bhutan
bangladesh
if you look at the health
in this indexes index you will find
bangladesh and bhutan has
better life expectancy at birth what we
call
lev and that has not happened in india
if bhutan can do that and bangladesh
can do that and they they have been
using digital health
quite effectively my specific question
is how will the health insurance
industry respond to that growing demand
for virtual health that's one and do you
think
things can also go the way you talked
about silicon valley or
i'm talking about never next door bhutan
or bangladesh
is that likely to happen in india also
in days to come
so the problems for the two categories
are different and
my response was more for the set of
customers the top five ten percent of
the population who buys health insurance
goes to the top you know corporate
hospitals and you know i was
responding for that segment but even if
you look at
the the strata which doesn't get proper
health care
right and our traditional approach as a
country has been that
you have to have uh you know these uh
primary health centers
a doctor after his mbbs has to go to a
village and spend
you know two years of his or her time
and that's how you thought you would
provide
health care that's not worked and that
is not going to work in future
but today you have the ability and the
technology to
provide health care at the doorsteps in
remote
india again using digital health
you can actually look at some of the
data
and so what you can do is have let's say
an asha worker
marginally trained using a tablet
with an ai engine behind or a virtual
doctor behind
which can provide the same level of
service in a village
and using that you can actually
aggregate data much better you can
figure out that there is an epidemic
that is
bubbling up in some small part of the
country
much earlier than uh in in the current
approach that we have so there is a huge
opportunity if we can
actually leapfrog the thought process on
health
using the current technology that is
available and becoming available
as we speak to transform health care and
obviously there's a
huge need that we need to do and we need
that we have as a country
in terms of doing that fast right sir
asha has been
quite a revelation and unfortunately in
india
despite it being a great success story
we have not been
able to exploit their the kind of
services they have been given
particularly in the village in
kerala i have first-hand experience
interacting with our
workers there so they have been doing
well and i i have a feeling asha
if the other experiment carried forward
can
transform the face of indian health
insurance
to a great extent the kind of gadgets
they are using the kind of data you can
gather
yes will you like to take some more
questions if you
i can take a couple of more questions
thank you so much something at 7 30.
right sir uh i
have few questions coming uh one
question is some brokers that lack i.t
infrastructure
are now having more difficulty providing
administrative services
how renewable information is now
obtained and how are
using data assumptions to solve this
so uh some of this broken firm
the question if i understand properly is
that
they have administrative challenges
because they do not have
id infrastructure in place so one is to
get the it infrastructure but even if
they don't get it
how are they going to deal with it
look i i'll obviously have to understand
the problem more
clearly but even you know any
organization be it a broking or an
insurance company
as i keep saying unless you build some
of these capabilities
you run the risk of losing out in the
marketplace
uh if your customer is not getting a
service from you because you don't have
the
let's say digital capability and the
customer wants insurance
he or she will shift to some other
distributor and there will be other
distributors who will invest
in technology so one thing that we are
happy to do as i see lombard is actually
happy to work with distributors in
enabling them digitally and
technologically so that they can
actually continue to do their business
we see it as a win-win for our
distributor and our agent and that's
what
i mentioned that's the kind of point
that i've kind of talked about when i
talked about hybrid uh
agency uh and similarly we've done for
small brokers
using some of our technology platforms
to uh allow them to
use them to sell policies but
you have to agree to use technology
without that it will become a
challenging future
another question is that why is it that
micro insurance or micro health
insurance not taking up in
india we have a very robust regulation
in place
and none of the neighboring countries
have that kind of regulation in place
despite the regulatory pro plotting
it has somehow not lived up to the
expectation of common people
micro health insurance is something that
can do wonders
going to the people who really need
health care more
as a rural people or the migrant
laborers
yeah there are i think there are
multiple issues uh the regulator is
now thinking of setting up separate a
kind of a regulatory architecture for
micro health insurer micro
insurance companies with less capital
i'm not sure that is going to solve the
problem i think the problem has to be
understood at the root
in terms of what does the customer need
and are we able to provide that
in a manner which is commercially viable
for everyone
and if you think about at the bottom of
the pyramid
uh we've done enough research and we
were probably the early companies in
terms of some of these uh
rural policies social policies uh back
in 2006 seven eight nine
to about 14 15 we were very active uh
i think one of the clear learnings is
that at that level
people have other bodies when insurance
is not the first thing that you buy
you know when you think of your uh
allocation of your monthly you know
budget there will be certain things that
will take priority over insurance at
that point
at that level of income and that's a
reality that you have to accept
and hence it is not as if someone who's
at a level of subsist subsistence or
barely making do
i think the first thing that they will
do when they earn a bit more
will be to buy some certain assets it
will not be to buy insurance
uh and hence uh i think the way
government is thinking about the ayushma
bharat initiative is probably the way to
go
we believe that's the right approach
that will address the bottom 40 50
of the population we have to as an
industry and policy makers come together
to figure out what happens to the next
40 because
the top 10 15 percent is covered through
retail and you know corporate
but the middle 80 middle 40 is what we
have to solve for
the middle po 40 is the real challenge
how exactly health insurance traveled to
them yes one last question
that i will ask and it comes from a
student and he asked me this question
what according to you are the skills
that a fresher need to acquire
to have to have before entering the
insurance industry they are all two-year
insurance students they we have retail
program also
we have the pg dm2 a two-year pgdm
course and
international business the four courses
we run here
and believe it or not we were the first
to start insurance code professionally i
know
i know and that's where we started
before the nine year also
yeah that's what was special about
whimtech right so that's why we keep uh
looking at looking up to webtech
so you know the one answer that i have
for anyone in any industry
is whichever industry you uh go in
uh first really understand the industry
understand whether what that industry
does is appealing to you
at the end of the day your value system
and the industry's value system has to
align
you know every industry has its own
purpose our purpose is really
to solve for the risk needs of customers
if you find that interesting join the
industry
if not find the industry that you enjoy
and and get excited by enjoying that
industry
now once you come in then it is all
about if you
enjoy what you're doing you'll find you
know you'll find ways to
do well in that industry and at least
what we talk about
in isis and lombard is uh attitude is
more important than
skills skills you can you can get you
can acquire
attitude is something that you have to
have so come in with an
open mind with a with an approach to
learn
and grow within the industry you'll do
well this is a techno marketing industry
right so we have to do
uh you know marketing of course but it's
a very technical uh subject
you know at times so you have to have
the interest to and the willingness to
learn
uh and that's why i keep saying you have
to have the right attitude
um and if you do that this is a very
exciting place
thank you so much for sir for joining
would have loved to hear you four hours
but
uh we will keep the time like 7 30 we
wanted to end
and uh thank you so much in fact
it was one of the most interesting
sessions
uh we had we have
the ex-member of
la member life iid a mr niles satya mr
arun agrawal mr
saket ketan mr kk mishna mr bidi
banerjee
and all our senior colleagues from
bimtech joined this
interesting discussion thank you so much
my turn is over i request saloni said
now to take over from here
thank you so much dr chatham i think the
questions
were so relevant and we have drawn a lot
of sensibility
thank you uh mr dhaas gupta for
addressing each of them
in such detail it's very encouraging i
thought
it's not easy for me to sum up what you
have said
so i was helped by dr chatrajis
he's always mentoring me towards some
new knowledge so he shared a mckenzie
report which was released very recently
and it was an insurance resilience in a
rapidly changing corona various world
on page number three there is a
paragraph which says about resilience
and return
weathering the crisis so for the benefit
of all i would like to refer to one
paragraph from that
because i thought it would add value so
it says given the uncertainty about the
duration of kobit 19
in individual markets a clear priority
is the development of contingencies for
the possibility of extended impact
including the potential for second and
third waves of the virus
building these contingencies requires
taking a hard look at the initiatives
that will improve both the use of
resources and
field productivity i think the story of
lombard has really you know taught us a
lot your initiatives have guided many
so at this point of time i think
malaria madam i will interrupt we have
three books
one written by professor kkc
this is a book sir we love to present
you
um it's written by professor k.k
cena this is another book by
the rajan
the third payloar sir dr chaturbai nisir
i'll request you to
honor mr das gupta with this book it's
not there with you so right sir
is it okay sir yeah thank you
and the third book i will ask mr ketan
sir to this is a very famous book by
bibek debroy
and anirban ganguly and
so this is third book sir uh mr ketan
please do the honor on behalf of bimtek
thank you so much for uh speaking to us
uh bhargav it is just
thank you thank you thank you thank you
my pleasure my pleasure saloni
uh professor please go ahead thank you
sir
yeah so uh this is a another big message
for all the aspirants here
uh read read read if you want to succeed
and you know therefore you have to just
pick up
anything and read so thank you uh so
much
uh professors for uh this moment
and uh strong message in itself so at
this point of time i'm just reminded of
a certain
sentence i read any kind of crisis is
good it wakes you up
so i think we all are awakened today in
ways so many
as an expression of gratitude i would
like to invite professor prateek
priyadarshi he is an associate professor
in the department here in insurance
department he's also
heading pgpx program they're doing some
great work over there
so i invite him to present the voters
thank you saloni ma'am um the the
biggest challenge for me right now is
that uh
my chairperson has stolen my thunder and
uh
sir uh doctor vedic said i would
formally like
like to lodge a complaint
see what happens is that after such an
enlightening talk uh such interesting
discussions
you know people are not interested in
listening to any other
talk that comes up their way but having
said that there are two things that i'm
reminded of sir
one is that interestingly and and
coincidentally
this is the period where in in the west
we call it the
thanksgiving week or thanksgiving day
and and and and saket
answer would agree that this is the time
when families get together to say thanks
to the nature and to the almighty
for the gifts that they have been
bestowed upon we in india talk about it
in terms of makhar sankranti and
and fungal and things like this but the
mood question is that
why do we say thanks the important thing
is that
we acknowledge the support the help
and and and the the gratitude that we
show towards
your help that has made this grant a
successor
uh honestly speaking said if we
if you were to take the total number of
questions that were put across to you
it would need at least six more hours
for this session to go on
and from that perspective i'm grateful
to the friends of bimtech
to my alumni and and to people
particularly
these industries from stalwarts uh
people like
mr bd banerjee people like mr arun
agrawal kkk mishraji
who was my my boss in the prep in the
public sector as also in the private
sector
and i had made a promise to him that i
would strive so that
i live up to his expectations and then
of course i would like to
show my gratitude and express thanks to
people like mr nilesh satay
you know having a member of the
regulatory board guiding us
is an awesome experience for us and sir
that would explain to you
why we have someone like vidisha in your
organization sir
we have always strived and this was
initiated way back in 2000 when
dr chatrovedy thought about starting the
insurance business management
that we have reached a stage where we
can truly say
that the world is ours would like i'd
also like to express my gratitude
to the entire i.t team in particular to
mr kapil gerk
of bimtech who made this entire
arrangement a flawless setup
so that we could have such easy
interactions i'm grateful to the people
who've come in from outside
particularly bangladesh the middle east
and of course nepal
we had uh we i sincerely missed mr
sanjaya dutta at the
colloquium and now that he's here i
would just like to
let him go with a warning you know next
time better be there you know buddy
i look forward to asking some difficult
questions from you
but having having having said that sir
uh i'm i'm honestly speaking overwhelmed
at the fact that uh you were able to
spare
almost two hours of your valuable time
in having a discussion
with the entire lot that that we are
here
so i would be failing in my duty if i do
not
talk about the most important aspect of
this entire
system that we have right now and that
is that the wake up call that you talked
about sir
i'm i'm really thankful to you that such
as a simple
message was communicated by you to the
entire lot of people who were
watching this in particularly to the
students
and and and the alumni that we have this
is the career path that one should look
forward to
so uh on behalf of uh director brimtech
on behalf of bimtech and on my personal
behalf
uh our gratitude my thank you and and
good wishes to you sir thanks very much
thank you so much thank you for having
me thank you thank you so much sir this
is
everyone yes
i'm so sorry to uh you are not with your
family loki puja is such an important
festival for bengalis
uh thank you so much sir for coming my
pleasure thank you thank you for having
me thank you so much
thank you thank you thank you sir thank
you thank you everyone as a customary
note i would like to just
uh say a quick good wish to
everybody who joined us and gave us such
a wonderful energy
in this leadership talk series 2020.
we'll be back very soon
and uh keep spreading love compassion
and gratitude good night everyone
thank you happy diwali and happy diwali
to all of you happy thank you
so much thank you so much
you